Hi , Welcome to the "ThuisBuis" by Arkin.
アーキンの家へようこそ。
How nice of you to watch this video .
そして、見てくれてうれしいです。
My name is Selma de Vries
ええと、私の名前はセルマー・ド・フリースです。
I'm a mental healthworker within a number of departments of the Arkin organisation.
私はで精神的な世話人です アーキン内の部門の数
And as a heartbooster, I would like to read you a story.
そして小さな心の要塞の野蛮人のように 私はあなたに物語を読みました。
I think it is an optimistic story.
それは。 楽観的な話だと思います。
In the past we have used it for easter celebrations , in itself this is remarkable ,
私達はまたそれを使用しました イースターのお祝いとそれ自体です
since it is an eastern tradition ,
特別な、それが出ているので 伝統を支援します。
But most universal .
しかし、超普遍的です。
It's about being human.
それは人間であることについてです。 ええと。
It's titled the cracked bucket.
それはひびの入ったバケツと呼ばれています そしてそれはあなたに読みます。
And I'm going to read it to you.
ひびの入ったバケツ、
A water-carrier in India had two big buckets, on both sides of the yoke.
2人のインドの水運搬人 ヨークの両側にある大きなバケツ
That he wore on a yoke on top of his shoulders One of the buckets was whole,
彼は肩越しにぶら下がっていた バケットnバケットは完璧な状態でした。
while the one was cracked on the side.
しかし、他のエメリーは持っていました 側面のひび。
So while that second bucket at he end
つまり、最後に2番目のバケットがあります
of the long road between the river and the house of the master of this water carrier
川との間の長い道の この水運搬船の主人の家
still was filled to the brim with water , the other bucket was half empty
まだ水でいっぱいだった、 他のバケツは半分空でした。
And this carried on like this for two full years .
そして、それは行きました。 2年間のフロート
the watercarrier delivered always only
常に配達される水運搬船
one and a half bucket to his masters house .
1.5バケツの水 彼の主人の家。
And of course the full bucket was most proud of his performance , since he knows
そしてもちろん、良いバケツは特別でした 彼が知っているので彼の業績を誇りに思う
exactly what is was made for.
もちろん正確に それが何のために作られたのか。
That other poor cracked bucket ,
その他のひびの入ったバケツ。
was hugely embarresed
彼はとても恥ずかしかった
about its defficiency.
彼の欠如のために。
and he felt miserable that he could only perform half ,
そして彼は彼だけが惨めだった 半分は彼のために、のために実行することができます
for his own master , the watercarrier ,
彼自身の人々のために 水運搬人を連れて行った人。
than what he actually was supposed to do.
彼が本当にすべきだったこと。
and after having annoyed himself over this , and ever more ,
そして彼がそこで2年間過ごした後 非常にイライラし、感じ続けました
started feeling bad about himself , felt really bad , started
しかし、自分自身について気分が悪くなり始めました、 完全に気分が悪い、それは始まりました
to talk spontanously to the watercarrier by the river.
ただ自発的に話している 川沿いの水運搬船。
he said , i am embarresed and I want to apoligise to you.
彼は私が恥ずかしいと言った そして、私はあなたに謝罪したいと思います。
But why said the watercarrier ?
しかし、なぜ水運搬船が必要なのでしょうか？
Why are you ashamed ?
なぜ恥ずかしいのですか？
I am because during de last two years ,
過去2年間、私は
i have managed to deliver only half a bucket of water to your master .
バケットの半分しか使用できませんでした マスターに水を届けます。
because of the crack in the side of the bucket , i am losing water continously on the way to my masters house .
私の側壁のその亀裂を通して 私は行く途中で絶えず水を失います
and because of my failure to deliver more water you have to work harder and surely you are not getting
私の家、あなたの主人の家 そして私の父はあなたをとても一生懸命働かせます
the wages you are supposed to earn .
そして、あなたはおそらく全額を支払わないでしょう あなたが実際に稼ぐものの。
The watercarrier began to feel sorry for the old cracked waterbottle
水運搬船は本当に同情しました この古くて貧しい、ひびの入ったバケツ
and he said , you know what , if we go back to the masters house in a little while ,
そして彼はあなたが後で私たちが知っていると言った マスターの家に戻りますか？
you should pay attention really well .
そこでは細心の注意を払う必要があります。
JUst have a look at the beautifull flowers by the side of the road.
その美しいを見てください 道路脇の花。
And indeed as they walked up the hill,
本当に、 彼らが丘を歩いていると、
the cracked bucket saw beautiful wild flowers indeed
ひびの入ったバケツ どこでも美しい野生の花
everywhere by the roadside This comforted him a little bit.
道路から離れて、それはもたらしました 彼を少し慰めなさい。
but at the end of the journey he felt unhappy all over again
しかし、旅の終わりに 彼は再び不幸を感じるだろうか、
since half of the water had been spilled again.
再び半分 水が流れ落ちていた。
Again he apoligised to the watercarrier.
そして彼は再び謝罪した 水運搬船で。
and the watercarrier looked at he bucket and said :
そして、水瓶座はそれを見ました バケツと彼はシラミを言った。
hay listen , havent you noticed that the beautifull flowers only grow
ただあるのを見たことがありませんか
by your side of the road ?
美しい花が育ちます 道路のあなたの側に？
Not by the side of the perfect bucket.
完璧なバケツの側ではありません。
and thats because , i knew all along water was leaking on your side of the road.
そしてそれは私がいつもaltijdを持っているからです あなたが少し水を漏らしたことを知っていました。
and i have taken advantage of that.
そしてそれを利用しました。
i have sown flowerseeds by the side of the river
私はあなたの側に花の種を植えました 道路を離れて、私たちが毎回
and everytime we return from the river you water them.
川から戻ってくる あなたはそれらに水をまきます。
and this way i have been able to collect beautifull flowers for two years
そしてそれが私が2年間やってきた方法です 毎回美しい花が咲きます
to be able to decorate my masters house .
の家の周りを選ぶ 私の主人を飾るために。
If you wouldnt be the way you really are
だからあなたが今のようでなかったら
than this house wouldnt have been a beautifull as it is.
あなたがいると、彼の 家はこれほど美しくはありませんでした。
that crack wasn't just another crack or it's always more than a crack.
その亀裂は単なる亀裂ではありませんでした またはそれは常に亀裂以上のものです。
and i think if there comes a time when we will.
そして、私は今までに 私達は私達が気づくところにいます。
all realise .
全員。
that we are not perfect.
私はそうだと思います、ほぼ全世界 私たちは完璧ではありません。
We are not invulerable , and we are not perfect.
私たちは無敵ではありません 完璧ではなく、すべてを作ることができるわけではありません。
yes cracks are part of it too , and we all have them.
はい、亀裂はその一部です そして、私たちはそれをすべて持っています。
and is this always bad ,
そして、それは常に悪いことであり、私たちはすべきですか
and should we always feel inferior because they may not be perfect?
常に劣っていると感じる 彼らは完璧ではないかもしれないので？
I think a whole different thing might be going on.
とても何かがあると思います そうでなければ可能性があります。
Leonard Cohen made a song called Anthem
レナード・コーエン、彼は歌の国歌を持っています
and there  is a beautifull sentence in that song.
歌からそしてその中に 美しい家族です。
a few beautifull sentences actually.
ええと、いくつかの美しい文章。 ええと、そのような。
there's a crack in everything
進行方向のひび割れ。
yet again he states : There is a crack in everything
もう一度あなたが彼女が割ると言う すべてのペットの値で。
thats where the light comes in
彼女は
everything and eveybody has a crack at some point in time.
みんなみんな バッジを壊したことがあります。
Or isnt perfect.
または完璧ではありません。
But because of that crack light can penetrate.
しかし、その亀裂のために 光を透過することができます。
I think if you have known for a longer time , that you are not perfect.
あなたが長い間あなたを知っていたなら私は思う 完全ではないかもしれません。
by no means , you are done .
ええと、それはそれを意味するものではありません あなたが取り消されたこと。
on the contrary , you can utilize it
実際、カートを使用してください。
It can lead to something beautifull
それは時々非常にうまく何かを成功させることができます。
In this case of the bucket story
あなたのバケツのこの物語の場合
the beauty is in the flowers
清潔で自然です ええと花。
that flourish by the roadside.
道路脇で育っています。
but i think that all of us , with our tiny crack(s)
しかし、私たちは今、すべて一緒にいると思います
and everything that comes with it we still can mean the world to each other.
私たちの亀裂、すべてのトリミングも お互いに大きな意味を持つことができます。
So my wish is that through evey crack ,.
だからみんなで願っています スクラッチええと光が輝くことができます。
light will be able to shine through
ええと。
and that this light will keep us upright with each other.
そしてそれは私たちにも少しありました お互いに追いつきます。
In any case ,
いずれにせよ、質問はしないでください
let us not be ashamed by a crack , but walk the extra mile for the other person.
存在することを恥じて、それ 他にコミットします。
i wish you the best , .
お大事に。
a good day , a good beginning .
こんばんは、こんばんは。
if you look in the morning ,
あなたが 朝かとてもおやすみなさい。
or a very good evening
うーん。 ええと。
that we can look at ourselves with mildness.
彼女は親切に私を呼んでいますか 自分自身を見るために。
untill next time !
次回まで